i like to think of them as content
buckets or
pillars and you pick three
and stick with those for a little bit
try a few ideas in each bucket
see what's working what's not scrolling
through the app
is the best way to kind of keep on top
of things and then you have to like
be able to think really fast and post
really fast because these trends come
and go
[Music]
hey you're listening to the sub club
podcast a show dedicated to the best
practices
for building and growing subscription
app businesses we'll share insider
secrets from the top subscription apps
on the app stores
let's get into the show welcome to the
sub club podcast
our guest today is maddie kirby senior
social media manager at one second every
day
she began her career in social media
marketing at toy company oswest
while working there she also started
growing her personal social media
presence accumulating almost 400
000 followers on tiktok in 2019 maddie
joined one second every day where she
has been
instrumental in leveraging tiktok to
organically drive millions of downloads
welcome to the podcast maddie
thank you i'm excited to be here i'm
also here with david my guest which i
forgot to introduce in our freaky friday
intro swap i usually do the intros but
that was great jacob that was fun
yeah you know what i'm very very very
versatile got to mix things up
so i i'll i'll pass back to david
because he's the one who preps all the
questions
nice um yeah so so maddie and i were on
a podcast
on a picus on a panel together earlier
this month an app promotion summit
which is a a great thing to watch we can
link it in the show notes
um but it was four of us on the panel
and it went really quick but
uh she shared a lot of really
interesting stuff about what she's
working on
in uh social media marketing and working
with one second every day
on their tick-tock presence and so i
want to bring her on the podcast to
actually give her time to talk a little
more about it in the context
of promoting apps because she's been on
a couple of other podcasts where
you're talking more specifically about
social media stuff um so yeah i'm super
excited to have you maddie and um
so i do want to to dive in and and you
know we typically do have more
developer focused guests you know people
are doing the coding or you know
focused on um user acquisition where you
know
spending 50k a month on facebook and so
that's another reason i was excited to
have you on the podcast is to just get a
really different perspective i think
that there's a lot of potential in
social media marketing
but not a lot of people talking about it
in the app space
and then or just knowing how to do it
right like are you how to even start
right especially if you're like a
developer turned
promoter right it's probably like the
last channel
you'll think of right i think right a
lot of app creators like tend to the the
things you were talking about david
those like
technical channels about buying ads on
facebook or whatever when
i don't know there's a lot of leverage
in social media stuff if you can do it
well
yeah absolutely so so i did want to kind
of start with
you know you got your start in social
media marketing not with an app
which is another thing it's like you
came to the app marketing with like such
a different perspective which i think is
is really good
there's too many you know people who are
just so narrowly focused
in in the kind of existing playbook for
marketing apps so
uh are there any lessons from your time
at a toy company
and of all the places that come from a
toy company is really cool so
um are any particular lessons from from
being at a toy company that you think
um you know helped you grow and learn
this form of marketing and specifically
that apply to subscription apps
yeah uh i don't know if it's necessarily
a lesson or lessons that i've learned
but i think coming from the toy industry
which is also an industry where people
don't leave it and they have a lot of
people that started in the industry and
then just
stayed there forever uh you have a lot
of people that aren't really
thinking beyond just what they are
normal
what they're used to i guess is what i
would say is what they're used to like
ads on nickelodeon that's all like yeah
it's definitely commercials like
they were still talking about tv and
trying to transition out of that that's
really funny that you brought that up
but that's kind of what we were
talking about at the time and so i got
really lucky and i had a great manager
who really wanted me to push people
outside of
uh their boxes and i feel like i
wouldn't have found tik tok
unless i was at a toy company because we
were so focused
on trying to connect to gen z and young
people
and i heard some kids talking on our
public transportation
about tick tock which was musically then
um
and i was like oh and i just had like my
feelers out about it because
i was just so focused on kids at the
time and like trying to find this like
cool new way that we can connect to them
and i downloaded it and i was a content
creator too so
i thought it was super cool so getting
onto tiktok at that time and super early
i feel like
wouldn't have happened without being in
the toy industry and also then i was
able to take that into one second every
day and
already had experience which i feel like
a lot of people don't really have
tick-tock experience coming into a
company
yeah that's really cool and so then what
was the leap like what what
um how'd you land the gig at one second
every day and decide to jump into the
the app industry
i was using one second every day already
before
even looking for a job so i had already
and i had known about the company the
company's amazing and they have a lot of
great benefits and
they care so much about the people in
the company itself and it's small
and uh remote so i was already hoping
that they would have a job opening when
i was looking
and i so i didn't necessarily have my
site set on an app really it was just i
was interested in one second every day
because i use it and i also like it
because it's content creation and i have
the background in that so i feel like
i was able to kind of have this weird
experience coming into it
you know i i i do want to pause real
quick and maybe talk a little bit about
the app
um and i should have researched i should
have read up on this before the podcast
but
it'd be fun to just ask um one second
every day has been around like
10 years right like this is the like i
think i bought this as a paid app in in
2009 or 10 or something so tell us a
little bit about the history of the app
itself um and what the app does yeah
so our founder has been recording his
life for 10 years now
which is a really long time and they
started on kickstarter
actually and he did a ted talk and
that's how a lot of people
initially found us was through his tick
tock where he had
left the ad industry um
for a year he left his job to go record
his life
his 30th birthday um and just
it's it was amazing and people really
connected to it and it's like a very
simple idea and then he did his ted talk
about it
and then that's how he he launched the
app and now it's just kind of
built slowly up uh through that um
really just being able to have him
connect with people
uh caesar is an amazing person and a
really great storyteller
and people were able to connect to him
first and then that's kind of how he
built a team
around him to slowly grow i love the
i mean i think you know when you talk
about user acquisition or
or you know ultimately that's you know
what marketing or whatever is right you
want to get people into your business
your app or whatever
um it always feels so much easier when
you start with the story
right when you start with like the
narrative the story then you add in the
business or the product later
right because now you have a foundation
i was i was on the one second every day
reading the timeline right it's all very
a clean narrative right like
this person has a story whatever and
then everybody can join in on everything
humans are very narrative driven right
so we like to be part of something that
like
that like makes sense right that like
has an arc to it so i think it's uh
i i and i think that downstream that's
gonna help will help makes
apps like one second be successful is
they have this like
something that makes sense and they
don't have to just go out and like oh
you need 50 000 users to spend 50 000
right um you actually have a little bit
of like organic story there it's great
yeah yeah and speaking of telling
stories so
while you were still at the toy company
you started building your own social
media presence so
you had uh your own personal tick tock
account but then also built up several
others
yeah what was it like i mean so this
again this as you said earlier this was
musically at the time before it even
became tick-tock before you even blew up
so you're really early to this really
cool platform how did
how did you build these um accounts
uh i started off at uh on vine
and then of course vine died r.i.p yeah
i know
i i had started it and then i had a
harambe vine blow up and then a week
later
they announced that the app was shutting
down and i was devastated because i was
like here's my shot i got it
and then so i was looking for
my next place to go because i was a
youtube kid growing up so i've always
wanted to make
videos and i and i love it just
naturally and i had some friends invite
me over to this app called flipagram
which is
actually kind of funny because that was
a competitor to one second every day
at the time and i didn't even know about
one second every day yet
um and so i was a paid content creator
over there to be using their app
um and then got onto tick tock
and started just posting random funny
videos and
at the time things were the algorithm
wasn't really developed then
it was more you post and then whoever
likes your stuff
is really important so if you have
somebody really cool and like big
that likes your video your video is
going to blow up and i just had
these two popular twin girls had liked
my video and i had all these people
coming over
and said that these girls had liked my
video and they saw it on their
uh platform or their account and then
that's how it started it just started
like going up and getting followers and
now
uh i have a an account where i play
guitar
i decided to take up learning electric
guitar and so i built
an audience of 11k on there in two and a
half months
so i'm really like addicted i guess so
yeah so
so and do you do you um you know i don't
know this is more about like personal
just like brand and like building these
these properties because
i mean i do think it's it's it's the
skill like you know we're talking about
developers building their own social
media properties it's like okay you got
to have
a stick right i don't know what you're
calling right guitar so do
do you carry them over from your other
properties you try to like bootstrap
them or you're just like nope
totally green field i'm just gonna like
be a guitar person now and like make it
a thing is that
is that more how it goes or i mean on my
other account my comedy account i guess
it's always been a really hard thing to
kind of stick with one thing that you're
into and some people are really good at
that i'm definitely
not the best when it comes to my own
stuff that i like
i i just want to do whatever and kind of
see if that works
but that's kind of morphed over time and
then with guitar i was just like i'm
just gonna
record myself playing guitar and see
what happens and it
did well oh so you don't you don't you
don't like plan out like oh i'm gonna do
a funny harambe guitar thing
it's just no i just do it it's a lot of
it's like improv and
going for it and just seeing and i think
that
being on the platform for so long i kind
of know what's gonna do well
yes yeah and sometimes you'll put
you know five seconds of effort into
something and it does really well and
then other times you put
you know an hour of work into something
and it doesn't do well this is me and my
twitter game
yeah you need to give me some advice
because like i can
i still can't 11 years in i sir 13 years
in on twitter i still can't predict
what's going to do well
yeah exactly so you you've kind of been
talking about your
your personal accounts um but
these things that you're saying i would
assume also apply to company accounts
and i would assume you know growing a
company account
you just need to have a similar amount
of exploration
so how have you taken those lessons from
your own personal accounts
and then systematize them
to to grow a company account and then
even
pushing back on on
not overly systematizing because you
have to keep experimenting
yeah that's a really good question i
think how i tackle it now since i've
been on so many accounts
uh because i grew one um back at the toy
company
too for the stop-motion animation toy
and that's kind of my first
dipping into that and we grew really
fast like it's like at a half a million
now
for followers but uh i think that's kind
of when i was realizing that there's
buckets
to these things and like i like to think
of them as like content buckets or
like pillars and you like pick
three like i'm gonna do behind the
scenes videos i'm gonna do
uh some kind of like app walk through
maybe for one second everyday purposes
and then fun trends
and stick with those for a little bit
try a few ideas in each bucket
see what's working what's not and then
kind of maybe
if the behind the scenes stuff is not
working as well then we won't make as
many of that stuff
and then just scrolling through the app
is the best way
to kind of keep on top of things and
make sure that you're experimenting with
new stuff because people are always
thinking of really creative ways to
make new videos and have these like wild
ideas that you don't think could ever
relate to one second every day but they
can
and then you have to like be able to
think really fast
and post really fast because these
trends come and go so that's kind of
like
my system i guess how do you avoid the
uh what's it that steve buscemi meme
that's like hello fellow kids like
how do you like how how do you because
that's always my fear too
it's like if i'm trying to be like hip
on twitter or whatever
like it feels like there's this uncanny
valley that brands can really easily get
into and you see it with like bad social
media right
is there is there is a solution just
hire people who are actually good at
social media or like
or is there like a framework for not
becoming the steve buscemi meme
i think the biggest thing is don't try
to
make anything that you don't understand
already like don't try to guess
i i think i learned that david i
cancelled this the the sea
shannon's revenue cat collab because
yeah i still don't understand it yeah
it's uh
i think i learned that on my personal
account uh specifically just
as i age and everything and you get like
these young kids on there that are like
wait you're
you're a millennial that's really old
and then they just kind of like it
pierces your heart a little bit and
you're like oh god that hurt really bad
but okay
thanks for for reminding me and it's
okay
if they do that it's actually kind of
funny and you can lean into it uh
but don't try to be gen z i think is the
big thing when you're trying to relate
just as i wouldn't try to
be boomers either like you wouldn't try
to
be somebody else so it's being yourself
knowing what you know and like not
trying to guess
at it and you can talk to that
generation
but they might just tell you like stop
get off the platform
or something i don't know but there's
always people that you can find within
the platform that will relate to you too
that's a big thing how much of this do
you think
is kind of product
social media platform fit
i guess so my question is like
can you shoehorn a product that wouldn't
necessarily
work on social media into social media
marketing
so revenue cap being a good example you
know we are
you know sharing some videos on twitter
and stuff like that
but it doesn't feel like tick tock would
be a good
platform for us to invest in marketing
wise
as opposed to because because we're an
infrastructure tool
right as opposed to you know it sounds
like even at the toy company the
stop-motion
animation product was what really hit on
social media
did you try other um products within the
toy company that didn't hit or
and do you have any kind of thoughts on
that kind of product platform
fit that's a good question we
specifically got onto tick-tock because
of the stop-motion toy and i think it
definitely makes it easier when you have
a content creation tool
because we had an app that went with
that toy too and
and really it's all about entertaining
people at the end of the day on tick
tock and if you can't make entertaining
content
with your product then it gets harder
i don't think we tried
with other products we did do uh
cross promotion where we would have like
the stop motion toy playing with our
other toys that we had
kind of thing and that was a fun way to
do it but we we had different strategies
for other toys like influencer marketing
or unboxing videos
as well um but i think that anybody
can be on tick tock but i also like to
ask people why do you think that you
can't be on tik tok
and often people will say well it's
because kids are on there
it's a kid's platform and it's really
not at all it used to be it used to be
people just lip syncing
and that's what i had started out doing
and i was terrible at it and like this
sucks
i am not this is not a good platform for
me and it's really just
transformed into a place where anybody
can kind of find their
their audience and and maybe with
revenue cat
it might be a thing of just trying to
explain what you do in a really fun way
and unique way
to make people excited about it there
are other developer brands that
find success on there right there's like
a certain language or that that works
yes it's just like
yeah you know for us it's always and i
think for any any you know as an app
i think going back to your point david
about product
network fit right apps in general fit
well i just think about one second every
day and tick tock right you're putting a
camera at your face or that's something
right so like
you're already like you know very like
products in some ways so it's like
very smooth transition um but for most
apps it is right you're there you're on
your phone you're doing stuff you're
probably bored
like here like let me tell you about
some other
application you can use it's a smooth
transition
um but then like i still like yeah
thinking about
i mean we have this problem now maybe a
podcast we do it's one thing but then
like
um you know for blog content and other
things it's really hard to come up with
stuff
that matters right that like like you
were saying maddie like
something that that that's funny like
you care about right that
that's like what you want to do because
like at the end of the day if you're
just trying to like
chase the meme it's going to come off as
hokey right it's going to come off as
like
un genuine um so
but i think app developers yeah i mean i
i i it feels like
we've heard like this whole tick tock as
an app
distribution mechanism really has
kind of something that yeah surprised me
too like it blindsided me it's like
we and not just the first order of like
we're selling ads on tick tock this like
second order
user generated content stuff which i
think is just fascinating
yes and i i think that again it's
you just have to figure out how you can
be on the platform if you want to and
there's really nothing to lose
with it too because it doesn't cost
money to be on there and try things like
you can have a podcast format
on there you can take clips of a podcast
and put them on there and people have a
lot of success doing that
or just having their reply with video
feature there's a lot of different
kind of structures that people it's it's
not just
making skits or trying to use popular
sounds
popular sounds do well but maybe that's
not for you
i think it's brainstorming trying things
seeing what sticks
and if it doesn't stick then try
something different and if that doesn't
then you can focus your energy
somewhere else and realize that you you
know you gave it your best shot
and maybe there's a different kind of
opportunity that comes up later or a new
feature that's introduced later that
works better
on the on the trend chasing um
what are some examples of that with one
second every day that you feel like
came off well and and can how do you how
do you attach yourself to a trend
without
that hokiness because it sounds like
y'all succeeded at that
but i imagine that that is a hard thing
to do so any tips on on how to do that
well
we kind of get lucky sometimes and that
is kind of like how
tick tock works is luck and i hate
saying that
prepared though yeah i mean it's good
that we were on tick tock
it definitely helps uh to be able to to
see what's going on out in the world but
we just had a a wall street journal
article that was about this too
about tick tock in one second every day
and how there's this trend going on
on uh tick tock where people are making
one second everyday type videos and
there's a lot of trends out there that
show it's like the 27 video challenge
where you have 27 videos and you set
them to a song that's very
we say that's one when sc vibes when we
ever like share it
inside of our our slack channel i mean
the thing is it's like
bad posts nobody sees right
like is is that true like it's kind of
it's like such a timing thing and that
goes back to the luck part of it
and i think being able to um
jump on a trend it's like you could have
a great video and people think it's
awesome and you show it to your friend
and they think it's great and it just
doesn't do well at the time and you
could post it two months later and it'll
do great
maybe not for a trend it's it's
randomness and
kind of like just how the algorithm
works with wanting to reward you
sometimes
but i think where we've done well with
uh jumping on a trend too is we had a
video that
took off with um one of my co-workers
made
she she helped me make it um she was
just standing there with her phone
and was having somebody else zoom in on
her that said
i recorded one second every day of my
life for the last year
and then it just rotated through like
really really fast imagery
of the year and that was a trend of
people showing it but it was like this
we just kind of twisted it a little bit
to make it about one second every day
but don't ever make it like an ad
it shouldn't be it shouldn't feel like
one second every day is posting it and
that's really cool we were getting a lot
of positive feedback on the post because
people were like
okay uh what's the app that you used
yeah and that's not a bad thing people
think that's a bad thing to have people
ask that but it's actually not it just
means that they think that some
random girl posted a video not a brand
and i i was on your brand account though
yeah it was on our brand account we get
that
all the time i mean that's a good sign
of success right yeah yeah
people don't really read the
they don't read the captions maybe i'm
not sure what it is
but they don't make that connection it's
really understated on tick-tock right
yeah kind of like floating in the bottom
yeah i feel like
it's a great thing when people have no
idea that it's coming from a brand even
when it's posted
on a brand account and that's i would
say with trends it should feel like that
it shouldn't feel like
like i'm trying to think of an example
like if oreo cookies
made a thing it shouldn't feel like they
are just trying to sell you cookies it
needs to be entertaining it needs to
tell a story
you can't just find an easy way to do it
and hope that it works so how how so
you've had success with first party
content have you used
like user generated stuff as well have
you tried to i've seen a lot of apps do
this where they'll
i i we know if we've had on the podcast
people before who have had like
tick-tock influencers make
videos and then use those as ads have
you experimented with any of that
we haven't used any as ads something
that's kind of
weird about one second every day too i
mean it also just has to do with us
being a small team
um with not a lot of money to spend
on ads so we really lean into organic
because organic has also done really
well for us so why would you spend a
bunch of money yeah
but my my manager who used to be the
social media manager when she started at
one second every day
started a thing uh where they added a
feature actually
to get more spikes monthly and that was
to make it so that people could match
their month
and share their money uh on social and
then they had a giveaway that went with
it and we still have that giveaway
and that gets hundreds of people to
enter by
sharing their their their month
essentially
uh of one second every day and that just
keeps that going
and just feeds into it and then the more
people that post about us
the more people that download and then
the more people that can then post about
us again
so it's just keeping that stream it's a
virality yeah
do you have it does it get posted tiktok
as well as like other platforms or is it
like specifically focused on tick tock
uh that's for instagram actually
yeah you have that one sorry i'm this is
i'm totally like a tick-tock
idiot but like you can't actually like
post videos into tick-tock right
or no you can oh okay you definitely
can't i know nothing about this yeah
yeah
no and we we share user-generated
content all the time on instagram and
we're trying to do that
on tik tok as well but it's it's not the
same because you can't really just share
a one second every day video from a
random person that doesn't mean as much
as trying to kind of make it more of
that tick tock format or
putting a little bit of context behind
it so that people understand it
so and uh on the on the panel we were on
you talked about
um how well it's done for y'all
at one second every day um can you uh
rehash what you already said but on here
tell us
more specifically about uh a couple of
the posts that went viral and then
being able to see the direct results on
in
downloads yeah so we started our tick
tock
uh in december because we wanted to be
able to launch it before the new year
which is our
biggest time of the year because that's
usually when people download
and then because it's the start of the
year that's a great time to just start
a thing for your life and then they'll
wait a year to post it
uh and so usually we see like this
massive spike because everybody wants to
post their year
uh but this time what was different is
that
i think it was the day before the new
year a girl
i was just randomly scrolling through
tick tock and a girl had made a video
that was like
hey i have an idea what if we just
recorded one second every day of our
life and then we would have a live movie
and then i went oh that's our app
and it hadn't even been i don't think it
was even at
one million views yet and so i was like
i gotta do a duet right now
and so i filmed a duet where i just was
walking through the app um
as she's explaining this idea and people
even thought that we made the app
because of her idea how did you guys do
that so fast
we're amazing uh so then people thought
it was like this new
cool app and uh it started this like
micro trend
uh through tick tock and her video i
think it reached a lot of
millions of views i think it was like 13
million or something crazy
and then ours got like a million views
and then everything after that for a
couple days was like a million on our
own account
because then everybody started
translating her video
into their own country languages and so
you had
hundreds of people copying her video and
just
ending up on everybody's feed and then
everybody that had already downloaded
one second every day and knew about it
was commenting inside of those videos
saying hey
download one second every day so they
were doing our job for us really
you know that's a sign of a great
product right like
yeah it is it's like we we talk about it
because we go i mean it's
again kind of a lucky circumstance of
having this girl
think of this idea that's really similar
to our app but also
we were able to capitalize on on it even
more because we do edited with
it and then we were able to grow an
audience to like
now we're at i don't even know we're at
20k or something
on uh tick tock but we we grew
really fast within that time and then uh
kind of going back to being able to see
download spikes
is we got uh number one in the app store
that day for the first time ever had
never had that happen
uh and it just i mean it blew the other
numbers
just away dramatically and then uh
now we're able to see these little
spikes every month when a tick tock is
posted from somebody
we had one in france and you'll see all
the downloads that happened in france
just
spike up and then we had one in
argentina and that spiked in uk
so being able to like see that and
also just learn from them like what kind
of videos are they posting
super simple them just saying i've been
recording my life for
this long people just think that's cool
because they're like
you did what you recorded your life for
four years what
how do i do that and then you tell them
how they do it and then they just
they're all like talking in the comments
it's really cool
and but we haven't seen this at all on
the other years
it's only this time that we've seen
these like massive monthly spikes too
didn't y'all hit number one again in may
or something
we did for a different country and i
think that was
argentina which we had never done before
it's just like a random
country but you could connect it back to
one tick tock
wow yeah we've seen i mean we had david
smith on the podcast a couple weeks ago
uh and his app uh widget smith like
exploded
for because of that and like uh he it
was just
somebody made a video right david that
was a story for us like
it was it was the same thing it was like
not they didn't pay for it somebody just
like show how to do a cool thing with
this guy's app and it
was i mean from our perspective we
talked about it on the podcast at the
time but from our perspective we
we provided his infrastructure for
purchases and we were like what the hell
is happening
like uh it's it's it's amazing one i
mean i don't know it's like computer
brain guy but like
with this like interconnected like we've
really like shortened the loop for like
the the just like mimetic energy to like
move around right
like people can like spike this stuff um
and it's
yeah it's it's it's mind-blowing the the
because we've seen it also
not just we just we've seen other apps
too like you know it's hard to move the
needle
for our infrastructure because we're for
thousands of apps but in tiktok
and like some of these and just to a
lesser extent instagram
can still like drive events that show up
on our graphs like what the hell is
happening
we had one that was a paid one like a
kardashian driven one that
obviously it's different because you're
paying an influencer but um
but but yeah it's it's it's incredible
and going back to your point about it
being
organic right first or like earned you
could call it two right it's earned it
was organic
but watching it and being there
you know for for you as the first party
like to take advantage of that i think
is as important as trying to be like
you know creating your own content right
it's probably yeah
yeah as beneficial i mean it wouldn't
have
gone as well if we didn't have uh a
presence
on the platform too and i think that
just goes to show that you should just
be on the platforms and have
a voice on the platforms for that moment
uh you shouldn't be just jumping on
i think there's probably like examples
of that with other brands
like the cranberry juice like ocean
spray
stuff that happened i don't think they
had a presence on tick tock but then
they caught on real fast
but just imagine if they already did
have a presence and then people would
want to be posting about them more but i
think yeah just having a presence on
there
too when that's all happening oh i was
trying to place the meme that was the
guy with the skateboard right
yeah skateboard sorry yeah
yeah yeah it's that one uh no it's it
was really cool
to see that all happen and and be able
to
show numbers because everybody i mean on
the team
has everybody in general has opinions on
tick tock and when you're able to
actually just correlate
these things with numbers some people
the people that are number people
were just like mind blown they loved it
like this is great it sounds like the
algorithm is very capricious though it
sounds like it's very kind of
even even you even suggested that
there's like intentional randomness like
progressive randomness
there's yeah there is but then there's
also i've
made the video like the the four years
that i had captured kind of video where
you have
something playing the back like the the
app i have in the background and me just
sharing my story
i've done that three times i think and
every time it's done well
so you it also rewards you for doing the
same thing
over and over which isn't a good thing
and that's how you can get trapped
but it is a nice thing to lean on when
you're like we need a spike
let's do this kind of video did you
follow the uh the widget smith
and home screen customization thing that
blew up in the fall
okay i was just gonna do get your
thoughts on that but uh
yeah i mean like like jacob said it blew
up on tick tock and
i no i know what you're talking about
now yeah yeah yeah
when everybody was customizing their
screens to make it like a theme
and everything yep yeah and so that's
what jacob was talking about a minute
ago was that widget smith was
was kind of the center of all of that
and it
and then and they used revenue cat and
so it just blew up
um oh that's awesome but that was kind
of just this crazy viral
wave where what i thought was so cool
about
how that happened we talked about on the
podcast i won't go super into it but
she basically gave a tutorial of how to
use the app
which is like the best
onboarding you could ever hope for you
know it's like it is a
complex thing to like go set up a widget
and
and configure all these this stuff to
get the widgets to show up correctly and
it's all a hassle that you would
typically as a developer have to think
oh man i need to onboard the user i need
to convince them
that it's worth all of this hassle to
get some reward out of it
and then she goes and like i mean in
like
i forget it was like 45 second video
maybe even 30 second video
it was like here's how you do it and bam
like or
actually i think she said like she
showed the like home screen at how
cool and aesthetic it was and and then
then she showed how to do it and then
she and it was like
she it was like this perfectly scripted
marketing
onboarding thing of telling you how to
do it telling you the result
telling you it's worth doing telling you
it's you know it's worth the hassle of
going through these steps
and then showing you the steps it was
just amazing how
it wasn't an ad it was totally user
generated it just ended up being the
absolute perfect ad
because it was user generated and
because it was user generated she felt
like you needed to explain it all
and like tell that story um so yeah it
was just
it was just a really fascinating little
blurb lip
and then and then you know a lot of apps
have been going viral because of
tick-tock since then i forget there was
another
another one recently that was like super
random like some kind of calculator or
something
that got into the top 100 in the app
store oh that's cool
yeah so it's just crazy have you all
thought about
product changes to try to incent that
behavior to like try and
encourage folks to make videos aside
from you mentioned the like sharing
thing but there seems like there could
be other ways to kind of like
plant some more of those viral spikes
around
yeah uh something that we're working on
i don't know if i'm actually
probably allowed to say what it is
because it's not but yeah maybe i should
keep it secret
we have things planned we're thinking
about it yes we do
we think about ways that we can
incorporate it in the app and we want to
think about more ways
i mean we've had tick-tockers that have
influenced
product changes to just even the ability
to flip
like mirror their video i don't know if
you know what that trend is but there
was this
uh effect they had on tick tock that
would mirror your face and it makes it
look
bizarre when you flip it for some reason
it's a psychological thing
and so then everybody was telling us
that we need to
have a mirror button so they can flip it
back the correct way
and we made that change and people were
really happy so we definitely listen to
everybody
on social about stuff and yes
we do think about product changes and
are trying to think about more
for the future to encourage people to
post but definitely making sure that
there's no um
pay wall with that too is important you
know if you want to
make hay off of like organic or viral or
something like that it has to be
i've worked on several like viral
organic or viral sherry features like
stuff like this
the only ones i've ever had be
successful are the ones that are like
core
to the product which means like you have
to think about it early right you have
to think about it
early on i mean you can add stuff later
but like unless it's like consequential
or like easy or interesting like
it's not actually gonna get to that
viral coefficient that makes enough of a
difference
um but but doing the product work in
some ways is gonna be higher leverage
than like trying to make your nth video
right yeah it's just making the product
more shareable uh
yeah we'll go further we have those
conversations and people try to
loop in the marketing team too and pick
our brains about hey
we heard about this product request and
we want to know
on a scale of 1 to 10 how important is
this for the success of the app and like
how much is it going to affect it and
we'll talk about it and be like
well that filter is not really that
important you can hold off for
like next summer or something it's it's
having those conversations and
they're really important i think
everybody on the team talks together
about the features
what do you think are some other ways
and specifically getting back to the
algorithm
that that helps you stand out
so you like aside from trend chasing i
know
the like popular songs is one thing
right because
if you use the background audio
from a video that was trending the kind
of audio trends
separate from the video right or
separate from topics and things like
that are there any other kind of
tips and tricks to to help your video
stand out even if you're not
um you know doing specific kind of trend
chasing
that's a difficult one because that kind
of comes down to like you and your
personality
and what makes you different as well and
that's a really hard one that can take a
long time to kind of flesh out
but if you're not trend chasing it's
kind of playing around with features
in the app and kind of seeing new ways
that you can play with it i know i had a
video
on my own personal account that was
using their
voiceover effect that they have where
the text is read out by a woman
and i would misspell the names of like
popular celebrities on purpose and i
found out that i could actually drag the
misspelling
out of the video you couldn't see it but
it would still do it
and then i could put the actual person's
name so i could make it seem
like this voice is just completely
butchering
these names in the worst way and it went
viral
just like thinking of these like random
ways that you can use these features or
like tricks
is really important and it's super fun
and people
love it so i think yeah just diving into
using the app itself there's so many
features that go on and new ways that
you can use them and that's how you
stand out is just kind of making like a
little bit of a tweak
to something so i'll uh you know just to
look into the future because if it you
know having seen
having seen myspace and then now then
facebook become cool and not cool and
twit i think twitter's not cool anymore
probably not right now
i'm on there so no it's my social media
of choice tic tac is like
the rising cool like do you have any
like i mean you know imagine you're in a
multi-decade career of doing something
along those lines
do you do you think about or imagine
like what what might be next or like
what the kids
think what what the kid on the bus might
be talking about in in five or ten years
all the time yeah but i mean i
have been on new platforms all the time
too
and they just flop sometimes you'll
think it's a great thing but
it's often because people think they're
putting out something different and
they're really not it's just the same
thing but looks a little different
different colors maybe
or you can't force people to use
an app you can only get people to like
naturally
kind of come over there and a lot of
companies too will pay people to come
and use their app to seed it right
yeah to try to get people to come over
there and generate fake
viewers or fake users really um yeah and
that doesn't work either
so i i do think about it a lot i haven't
quite seen that yet for what the new
thing is i think tik tok has stayed
around a lot longer than i thought
because i remember talking about it with
people at vidcon a couple years ago
where we went when do you think vidcon's
gonna go just because we were all scared
because of fine when that drops i mean
that affected so many people and
it impacted them in a positive way too
because some people had already
set their sights on uh youtube or
doing tick tock it's either you chose
short form content
or long form so just being ready
don't have all your eggs in one basket
it's kind of like the big thing
and be looking and just be aware of
what's out there it doesn't mean that
the thing will be the next big thing it
just means you should be aware of it in
case it does become a thing
yeah i would say like taking your
company brand onto very unproven
platforms is probably not a great use of
time right like you want to wait until
there's something there
yeah i think it's with a smaller teams
it's definitely us trying to think is an
hour gonna really be worth it or is it
really more well spent
if it's an hour of me making some tick
tocks in my apartment
probably the tech talks right now it's
kind of a random thing but it's fun
but but how do you approach that then
because there is
value in the experimentation of like
seeing what's next so
do you kind of think okay i'm going to
waste
two hours this week checking out new i
mean you probably don't time box it like
that but
there is some value in that
experimentation
how much are you time are you spending
on on that experimentation
because it sounds like that's i mean
that's kind of been a theme of this
whole conversation is
try this try that see what sticks see
what happens so
and there's value in that so how much
how do you kind of
view that time that you're just throwing
stuff against the wall
uh it can really range and that just
depends on what apps are out there
our uh ceo caesar's awesome at
being in the loop with the tech world
and kind of seeing what platforms are
being talked about
on twitter so twitter still is a
relevant thing relevant for something
yeah early millennials
yeah aging out of anything relevant
exactly
like he sent us apps that were like whoa
this is really cool and even if it's not
something that blows up
it can still help us with our app too
and like internally
yeah we're like that's a really cool
onboarding video i have never seen
anything like that that's super helpful
and that
that's just the team being curious about
stuff and i think that's so important is
just
to also if you're in social media you
should just be i mean on social media
and i'm definitely on social media way
too much but
that's what i do with my own time too
i'm not like making an account for one
second every day on every new platform
that exists and like trying it out
i'm trying it out on my own own time
sometimes
like on my own account and that's the
best way is just to see how you like it
and how it's working for you and your
friends to use it
i can't remember what the app was called
it's like paparazzi i think
yeah maybe that's what it's called yeah
that went viral for four days or
something right this went viral for four
days or whatever
and it was great and we were like whoa
this is so cool that's like one of the
onboarding videos that were like this is
awesome it's got like
the the phone was like vibrating and
stuff while you were like going through
this
onboarding experience it was so cool uh
we didn't stick with it but that's also
because we're like we don't
have as many friends as like a bunch of
kids do so maybe that's a different
experience in their world maybe they're
all talking about it more
um but yeah i think just getting on it
and seeing it
can be a valuable thing and using it for
your own time
and actually creating content on the
platform is important
it's not too dissimilar from how
developers use new like
coding tools right like you try it for
side projects i mean it's one
channel for revenue caps talking about
our own growth is like we want to make
sure
like selling into bigger older companies
it's a little sometimes it's taking
longer we're able to do it now
but like it's much easier to win like
yeah the like inconsequential or less
consequential
side project uh and then you know ramp
that into something bigger later right
yeah
then sometimes a better place for that
experimentation definitely it's funny
i was thinking about it from an app
developer's perspective so we have the
tools guy
the social media person and the and me
as the app
uh focus so
exactly what you were saying is is how
you want to prove out your own app
like i've had apps where i send out a
beta and people stop using it like a
couple days later
and so you know when you go onto this
social media platform and you're trying
it and your own personal use just drops
off
then it's clear it's not as sticky where
most people get on tick tock it's like
they're hooked and they're going
i will not open the damn thing like it
is too good like i got twitter enough in
my life ruining it like i don't need
this other one yeah yeah but for but for
the developers out there
you know when you send out a beta you
know your beta people might not be your
exact target market but you should have
some level of like
stickiness in in the app the
signs of product market fit um anyways
i do want to talk a little bit and we
need we're getting short on time but
um you're launching a new community
feature with community manager or tell
me about that because i actually don't
know all the details
yeah uh i think you mean brand
ambassador program
that's what you're talking about yeah
yeah yeah yeah i
announced that on the panel that day
that we were launching that
and we had over like 200 applications
for people to join our brand ambassador
team
um and we have a marketing team of three
people to manage that team so we had to
narrow it down a lot unfortunately
but we had you know over 200 people
submitting videos of why they wanted to
be on this team
and this team is for us to be able to
connect with people in the community
uh to kind of just start a brand
ambassador program because we've always
wanted to do that it's been talked about
forever
so we just made the leap and we narrowed
it down to
um 26 people and announced them
last week and so we're getting them all
on boarded and ready to go
and we've got like people from all over
the world that are ready to make some
content about one second every day
but that's kind of the thing is they get
you know connections with us and can
have impacts within the app
as well as like free merch and things
like that uh that are really fun
and then uh we get some content from
them in exchange which is kind of like
the user generated
and hopefully we'll be successful and
we'll see some
like really cool things from them we're
just excited to see what they create
so so the so the goal is is to
be more directly connected
with some of the people who are already
creating content
in the space and then and it's not a
paid gig it's it's uh they like you said
they get paid in
in paid in merch right in merch and but
i imagine that's
not exclusive merch you can't put a
dollar value on it right yes yes
exclusive yeah what what i mean what was
the pitch to them
specifically yeah uh the pitch to people
in general was to be
a part of the community to identify uh
if you identify as a one-second everyday
fan which we've got a lot of big
super fans out there who have been using
the app for eight years to
you know a year and they just love it
and they just want to be
a part of that and really kind of make
their own with it
like if they're a writer they can submit
a blog post
if they uh really like social media they
can focus on tick tocks to make
uh for us to post and kind of like help
give them shout outs
they just really want to have experience
some of these kids are
uh some of them are like kids that want
marketing experience some people are
like
older that are just like i love this app
so much and i promise i will make the
coolest videos for you and here's like
what i do
and they're just so jazzed about it and
they're gonna get like the younger
people that are newer to the app
really excited so we're just excited to
see them
interact and everything and then uh
get content and like new ideas because
i'm just a
one person making stuff for social media
and i want to see kind of what people
naturally make we're not trying to force
them to make anything we're not telling
them that they have to make this kind of
video
it's just whatever they want to do and
then they can discuss within the
community
so i'd like to take this opportunity to
announce the revenue cap brand
ambassador program
uh david figure out the details i don't
know i don't know
you sort it for me this is this is
blowing my mind though i mean
and again i mean the whole reason i
wanted to have you on the podcast is
like you just are
thinking so differently i mean i know
brand ambassador is it
i just i've seen brand ambassadors i
know the general idea
you know but i just never would have
thought it could work for an app so it's
so cool
that that you all are just trying this
new thing and
having users help with your marketing
and yeah
and then being so like thrilled to do it
that's just incredible so much better
too than like a bunch of like stale
like uh like you know like facebook ads
you generated on fiverr
right like like get some real you know
it's so much more valuable that's mostly
how people find out about our app
is through word of mouth and people
posting about us so it only made sense
and
and we knew it was the right time
because we had all these people asking
if we had a brand ambassador program
and that's kind of like how we sold it
to the team too is being like hey
people are asking people are interested
this is the time
to do it and just try it there's nothing
to lose
let's go for it see what happens um and
then hopefully from there we'll be able
to just keep growing it
and we'll just have this like awesome
connection with our user base
and what's been really so cool about
doing this podcast and talking to so
many folks is that
different things just click for
different people so you know if you're
listening to this podcast you have an
app
that isn't content heavy you know maybe
social media is not the perfect fit
for you and maybe you're not going to be
able to have brand ambassadors and
things like that
but the point is you don't just have to
buy ads on facebook like there are so
many different avenues to explore
and this is one really cool way to do
something different
and to very cost effectively grow an app
without just dumping money into ads so
it's so cool
and we do need to wrap up um is there is
there anything else
you want to share we're going to put
links to your you know of course your
tick tock
and uh one second every day uh but
anything else you wanted to share as we
wrap
up i know i think that's that's it
thanks so much for
for having me i had a really fun time
talking about all this with you guys
this is like my passion so it's great to
chat
well thanks so much for your time this
is super insightful yeah thank you
thank you to make sure you never miss an
episode
subscribe to the show and your favorite
podcast player thanks so much for
listening
until next time